(The Thai people want...)
We need justice.
Bring our people back.
Hey! I said get out.
Hurry up.. Get out of the building.
Hey!
Hey! You guys.
Get out of the building!
Quick!
Go, go!
Hurry up.
Get out!
There is no one left here.
Hurry up! Quick!
Go go go!
How are things now, Ravin?
Have you cleared everyone out?
Done. Go!
Hurry up!
I think there's no one here.
You two, go check at the back building.
Where'll you go?
I'll check the leaders.
Wait, Ravin.
Be careful.
Come, Mada.
Go around that way.
What about the Law building?
There's no one left at the Law building.
I'll check at the Social Sciences building.
I'll check at the Accountancy building.
OK.
Be careful.
Mai!
Stop.
Hello.
What?
Remember to go to the meeting point
when you get out.
Our friends out there
are preparing to go to the forest.
If we want to reform the country,
we must go where there's opportunity.
Do you want to join us?
If so, what do I have to do?
I'll tell you where to meet later.
Lieutenant Det, could you allow me to see my son?
Please, Lieutenant.
Sure, teacher.
Thanks so much.
Vin.
Mom.
Vin, are you ok?
Did you get hurt?
I'll try to bail you out.
All of you, too.
Please calm down.
I'm here for the arrested students.
This way.
"When Light Fades"
(Episode 1)
Dan told me he'll come tomorrow.
Don't forget to thank him properly.
If it wasn't for him,
I wouldn't know how to get you out.
OK, mom.
He moved away a long time ago.
Never thought I'd see him helping us.
Guess we're lucky.
...have fled into the jungle to
join the Communist Party of Thailand.
Such actions are considered
a grave threat to national security.
I don't want you to join this.
Your duty is to study.
Leave the national affairs to the others.
Mom.
I just want to make this country better.
I went to the volunteer
camp in the countryside.
There's a lot of exploitation out there.
Inequality is everywhere.
I know you want to make our country better,
but there are many methods to do that.
Please don't follow the trend.
There's no need to go
to protests like this.
Do you understand me?
Yes I do.
My friends and I...
We might just be small, ordinary people.
But our hearts are 'great'
enough to believe that equality must exist.
No matter how much we must endure.
Because the people we love most...
Deserve to live in a better world.
My name is Ravin. It means 'The Sun'.
The sun's duty isn't just to shine,
it's to give light to everyone, equally.
And true light...
doesn't shine for itself;
it shines so that others can see the way.
Even the smallest person
can be a 'Great Sun'
for someone else.
Get off, kids.
Ouch!
Are we here?
Just answer this if you meet anyone.
"Though the sky is dark, the stars remain."
Yes sir.
Keep it quiet.
What's next?
Who?
We...
Though the sky is dark, the stars remain.
Is that all of you?
Good, let's go.
Uh... wait a moment.
I...
I have a stomachache.
Poo?
Stomachache.
Just wait a moment.
If you want to poo, go there.
The rest will wait here.
Any tissue paper?
Nope! Who uses tissue paper in the forest?
Beware of soldiers.
Phew! Almost didn't make it.
Do I really need leaves to wipe my ass?
Whatever.
Ouch!
Which way?
Ouch!!
Get up!
Sorry.
Thank you so much for saving me.
Be careful if you don't
want to die in the forest.
Thank you so much for saving me.
My name is Ravin.
You can call me Vin.
What do you want me to call you?
Comrade Yue.
Yeh... Yoh... Yeh... Yeow...
Yue.
Yea.
Yeah...
Yeww.
Yue.
Yea.
Comrade Yue.
Yeww.
Yak.
Stop.
Keep quiet, just follow me.
Yes, Comrade Yak.
What kind of person lacks social skills?
I think he's been gone too long.
I'm gonna go find him.
Please take care of the students.
Yes sir.
Hey! Why did you take this path, comrade?
What about the path you explored?
Why did you two come together?
Everyone is here. Let's go.
What took you so long?
I got a little lost.
I tripped.
Luckily, Yak saved me.
Yak? Is that his name?
Yep.
What the hell... Yak?
What a weird name. Yak? Seriously?
Yes it is.
My legs are dragging.
When will I get there?
Totally.
Ouch!
Let me carry your bag.
Have some water first.
It'll help you feel better.
Can I have some? I'm all out.
Umm.
Yak.
Yak, Yak.
How far?
A bit more... just go
over that mountain.
The mountain? A bit more?
Yak.
How far do we have to go to reach the base?
I think you're tired because
you're talking too much.
Just shut up and keep walking.
We're all tired. Can
we have a little break?
If you can't take this,
you should go back
to university, right?
Give it to her.
There's a stream up ahead, don't stop yet.
Fine, just a bit more.
Hey!
Drink first. Hang in there.
He said...
A-BIT-MORE.
Go.
Everyone.
Tonight we will take a rest here.
Phew!
Everyone is ready to eat.
Go ahead. I just wanna
rest here for a while.
If you want to stay together in the base,
stick to the rules.
When it's time to eat, you eat.
When it's time to work, you work.
Don't just do whatever you feel like.
Yes sir, Comrade Yak.
Why do you have to be so forceful?
Why can't you see the big anthill?
If it's a mine, you'd be done for.
This is for you.
Thank you.
Mr.?
Just call me Yaguar. I'm
only a villager who volunteered.
Thank you.
Sure.
Hey!
Come here, come come.
Come here. Sit together.
Hurry up, comrade.
Sit here.
Eat it.
It's OK. I can sit with my friends.
So you can eat your fill.
You can share with me.
Why share?
We got equally tired walking,
so we should eat equally.
Then we'll have enough strength to walk.
Eat it.
What is this meat? It tastes gamey.
It's dog meat.
We're in a forest, not in a city.
We eat to live,
not live to eat.
Eat it.
Sila.
As they said, we have to adjust to living.
If we can't bear this,
how will we handle tougher things?
It might be rough at first.
You should try to eat. It's cold at night.
Dog meat can keep you warm.
Mada.
It's not easy to find food in the forest.
If it's edible, eat it.
Please don't be a burden to others.
Isn't that too harsh?
It's alright, Mada.
Go take a seat.
Try harder, so you'll have the strength.
Come here, sit with us.
I want to sit with my friends.
Nope.
Let me sit with Mada.
Sit down.
Eat it.
Try harder, so you'll have the strength.
Yummy! I've never ever tasted it before.
So delicious, very delicious.
Good. So finish it.
Tomorrow you have to walk a lot.
Fine! I will.
Vin has been gone a couple of days.
I asked Mada's mom. She told me...
Mada has been gone with Sila as well.
I'm afraid, Dan.
I'm afraid that Vin would
have gone to the forest.
Don't worry, Aunt La-or.
I'll find out about Vin.
And will call you as soon
as I get the information.
Let me get the phone.
Sure.
Vin.
Are you hurt?
Don't worry. You will be fine.
Go rest up there.
Eat this, Dan.
It's good. You should try some.
Eat more, so you can grow faster.
I'll bring you home, Vin.
New Student List: Baan Saeng Dao Base.
Comrade Ploeng,
do you know Ravin ShineShan's background?
Have you been thinking about it?
Having the same last
name or being siblings,
doesn't mean they know each other.
Whatever happens out
there, stays out there.
Our ideology here is more important.
Ravin and his two friends
who are student leaders, are interesting.
They have passion and determination,
and can really help us with this mission.
We need justice.
Bring our people back.
We have no weapons.
Don't shoot us.
Don't shoot our people.
Help me, Vin.
Crying?
I had a bad dream.
I dreamnt about the university that day.
Forget about everything
outside of the forest.
You've chosen to be here in the forest.
So please stick to the ideology.
Follow our revolutionary path.
I know it's not that easy.
But that doesn't mean it's impossible.
I've been through it before.
How did you get through it?
You'll see.
Get some sleep, we've got
a long way to go tomorrow.
Thanks for taking care of me.
Are you OK, Mada?
How far does it take to reach the base?
Almost there.
Mr. Yak said almost there.
But I think it means
there's still a mountain.
Just keep walking. I'm too tired to talk.
That kid is really mischievous.
This is it. The entrance of our base.
(The villages surround the
city, the people must prevail.)
The newbie young comrades have arrived!
Welcome to Baan Saeng Dao's base, comrades.
One of the allies of
Communist Party of Thailand.
Welcome.
Yes! We're here.
Finally we made it!
(Comrades, victory belongs to the people._
Hello again, every new comrade.
From now on we are one family.
We stay together as comrades.
We'll share joy, pain,
and the same ideology.
Whatever happens outside, stays outside.
Here, we won't ask about
your past or background.
For security,
we use aliases
instead of our real names.
If anyone already has one in mind, tell us.
I will go by Comrade Gaun Hin.
I want to be like a rock.
Stay strong and unshakable for our country.
Mhm, good!
I will go by Comrade Meut.
I will go by Comrade Dum.
Mhm, Comrade Meut, Comrade Dum. Great!
Who's Ravin?
When did you create your alias?
The one who's talking to Comrade Gaun Hin.
People need to be prepared.
Do you think he is involved with that guy?
Don't know yet.
What about you two?
We haven't thought anything yet.
Well, you go by Comrade Ying.
Good. Thank you, Comrade Ploeng.
What about you?
He is Comrade Saeng.
All right, Comrade
Saeng. Then it's settled.
All of the new comrades
please get your personal belongings
at the quartermaster.
We will treat each other with honor,
and respect here.
Shit! I don't like the name
'Comrade Saeng', so lame.
We do not use swear words here.
Not even "shit" or "damn."
Shit! Me again.
He's just said not to use "shit."
If we're all clear, dismissed.
Hey Comrade! Take it.
Hand everything out.
I don't like the name "Comrade Saeng."
Comrade.
Wait a minute. I'll be back.
Yak. Yak. Yak.
Yak. Yak.
We already have a title.
You can call me a comrade.
Sure, Comrade Yak.
Please pronounce it correctly.
Comrade Yue... Comrade Yue! Comrade Yue!
Why are you hanging around me?
I want to know why you picked "Comrade
Saeng"? It's so outdated, and lame.
It suits you. Doesn't your
real name mean "the sun"?
Urgh!!!
Thank you so much for saving me.
My name is Ravin. You can call me Vin.
Oh, from when I took a dump.
Hey Comrade! Hurry up and take it.
Yay!
I'd go with that one over there.
Ugh... Argh!
Hey! Fine, It's yours.
I'll take the other one.
Let's see what we've got here..
Whoa, there's a flashlight!
Mmmm... A flashlight.
Are you OK, Comrade Saeng?
Hey Comrade Saeng! Don't you hear me?
Comrade Gaun Hin is speaking
to you, Comrade Saeng.
Shit! Did you call me?
No more "shit". You were just named
"Comrade Saeng." Did you forget?
Sorry. I forgot.
What are you trying to say?
I asked you, "Are you OK with it?"
Oh, that's it? No need to make
it sound so formal. That's easy.
Are you done with your belongings?
So go take a shower.
Finished.
Go take a shower.
Go take a shower. We're so stinky.
Get down.
Woohoo!
Finally, it's shower time! I'm so stinky.
Yay!
Woohoo!
This is not a playground.
If your noise drowns out the warning siren,
you won't escape in time.
Especially you.
What the hell? Why me?